Guide to the Papers of Robert Hunter 1699-1744 (Bulk 1710-1744) MS 316
New-York Historical Society
Robert Hunter Papers
1699-1744 (bulk 1710-1744)
New-York Historical Society
MS 316
0.5 Linear feet (1 box)
Robert Hunter was a colonial governor of New York and New Jersey. His papers include correspondence, accounts, and legal documents.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Biographical Note
Robert Hunter was born in Edinburgh, Scotland 1666. He was appointed governor of New York and New Jersey, arriving in June of 1710. Hunter left New York and New Jersey in 1719, exchanging positions with William Burnet, the comptroller of customs. In 1727 he was appointed governor of Jamaica, where he died in 1734.
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes personal and official accounts; bills of lading; receipts; letters of administration issued by Governor Hunter; powers of attorney; leases; complaints issued in suits against debtors; bills of exchange; bonds; a few items of correspondence; and a group of later legal documents pertaining to the affairs of Robert Orby Hunter, particularly to his suit against Peter Schuyler.
Individual documents include a list of warrants, bonds, conveyances, and papers left in the hands of Abraham De Peyster, 1719; accounts pertaining to the repair, rental, and leasing of houses and property in Amboy, New Jersey; and a 1720 valuation of Hunter's household goods at Amboy. Individuals mentioned or involved in Hunter's affairs include his attorney, James Alexander, John Barclay, and William Burnet.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into folders by type of material. Items within the folders are arranged chronologically.
Receipts (financial records); Powers of attorney; Letters of administration; Legal instruments; Debt -- New York (State); Land grants -- New Jersey.; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- To 1775.; Perth Amboy (N.J.); Accounts.; Bills of lading.; Bonds (legal records).; Complaints (Civil procedure); Correspondence.; Inventories; Leases.; Legal documents.; Alexander, James, 1691-1756; Barclay, John, active circa 1700-1740; Burnet, William, 1688-1729; Hunter, Robert Orby; Schuyler, Peter; Walbo, Richard; Eagle (ship)
- Series I: Papers
  - Correspondence addressed to Robert Hunter, 1711-1744 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Robert Hunter, 1723, 1726, 1744 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounts (including accounts of the Brigantine Eagle), 1716-1730 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abstracts of Accounts/State of Affairs, 1722-1734 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bills for various goods and services, 1718-1730 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, 1722-1731 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bills of exchange, 1713-1723 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bonds and Indentures, 1715-1742 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Leases for Hunter's property, 1728-1730 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters of Attorney, 1712, 1719, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters of Administration issued by Hunter, 1711-1717 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bills of Lading, 1724, 1727-1728 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Complaints issued by Hunter in suits against debtors, 1714-1744 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legal affairs of Thomas Orby Hunter (particularly his suit against Peter Schuyler), 1735-1739 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Petition to Hunter from the General Surveyor of New Jersey, 1716 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Releases, 1716 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Land transfer for property located in the patent of East New Jersey, 1699 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Inventory of the estate of Richard Walbo, 1710 (Box 1, Folder 18)